A Finding Aid to the John Graham Papers, 1799-1988, bulk 1890-1961, in the Archives of American Art AAA.grahjohn
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, circa 1852-1961; Series 7; 1 Linear feet Box 10, OV 16
  Sketchbooks include an early sketchbook with line drawings, mostly of horses, dated and inscribed by John Graham to his son David in 1934. One drawing in this volume appears to have been made by David Graham. Later sketchbooks are all dated in the last few years of Graham's life and depict mostly women, horses, mythical, and classical subjects.
  Sketches and Drawings range from very rough sketches and doodles to finished drawings. There is a large text piece done with stencils, and many figures, equestrian subjects, mythical subjects, abstract drawings, and few landscapes and still lifes. Illustrated folders and envelopes, some of which are dated, contain a wide array of symbols, decorations, drawings, notes, and lists on a range of subjects. Additional annotated folders are found in the Writings series. Illustrated folders closely resemble a number of Graham's notebooks, also found in Writings.
  Drawings which appear to have been made by others include several precise architectural drawings in pencil, one of which is dated '62, presumably 1862. There are also several equestrian drawings and a contemporary series of fantastical drawings of griffins and women, which do not appear to be in Graham's style. Prints include a series of illustrations of 19th century Russian Army uniforms and 19th century interiors which are hand painted, as well as fine prints of classical architecture and a couple of 20th century woodblock prints.
  Additional artwork is found scattered throughout the collection, especially in Personal Business Records, Writings, and Printed Materials.
  - Sketchbooks, 1934; circa 1960-1961; (6 volumes in 6 folders) (Box 10, Folder 14-19)
  - Sketches and Drawings, circa 1953-1959; undated; 4 Folders (Box 10, Folder 20-23)
    see also OV 16
  - Illustrated Folders and Envelopes, circa 1939-1961; 6 Folders (Box 10, Folder 24-29)
  - Artwork by Others, Drawings, circa 1862; undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    See also OV 16
  - Artwork by Others, Prints, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Artwork by Others, Silhouette of Maria Dombrowski, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Artwork by Others, Textile Print, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
    see OV 16
  - Oversized Artwork (Box 16 (OV))
    (See Box 10, folders 20, 30, 31, 33)